essortment.com 2015-05-11

# Privacy Policy | Essortment

**Effective Date: October 26, 2009**

This Privacy and Information Security Policy (the "Policy") discusses the personally identifying information ("PII") that we collect about you when you use our website (the "Site"). This Policy applies only to information collected by us or submitted by you through the Site, and not to any information collected or submitted outside of the Site.  

**Who We Are. We are Demand Media, Inc.  ("Demand Media," "Site," "we," "us," or "our").** Demand Media is a leading Internet registrar and syndicator of professional content and social media solutions. 

**This Policy and the Terms of Use.** This Policy is part of and incorporated into the Demand Media, Inc. [**Terms of Use**](http://www.essortment.com/disclaimer.htm) (collectively, the "Terms").

**BY PROVIDING PII OR OTHER INFORMATION TO US OR BY USING THE SITE, YOU AGREE TO THIS POLICY AND THE PRACTICES DESCRIBED IN THE POLICY.**

1\. INFORMATION YOU GIVE US

We collect any information you enter on the Site. The information that we collect varies depending upon how you use our Site.

2\. AUTOMATIC INFORMATION COLLECTION

2.1 _Cookies_. Like many websites, we use "cookies". Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser. We use persistent, identifying cookies to remember your information and to link your activities to you. While you can take steps to warn of, block or disable cookies, if you do, the Site may not function and appear as we have designed it. Nonetheless, if you want to take these steps, you can do so by following the instructions associated with your browser. Our cookies collect information such as: 

  * the domain name and host from which you access the Internet and the Internet address of the site from which you direct-linked to ours; 
  * the date and time you access the Site; 
  * your computer's IP address and information about its operating system, platform and the Web browser type and version you use; 
  * demographic and other non-personally identifiable profile information about you; and 
  * information to combat fraud or misuse. 

2.2 _Collection of Information by Third Parties_. Some of the advertisers and other businesses that advertise or place other content on our Site use cookies on our Site and may place a cookie on your computer. The content posted by these businesses will be identified as coming from a third party. In addition, we use third-party advertising companies to serve ads. These companies (1) use information obtained from your visits to this Site and other sites to serve ads to you and (2) place unique third-party cookies on your browser. Also, we use Web beacons provided by third-party advertising companies to help optimize our advertising. Web beacons enable us to recognize your browser when a cookie has been placed on your computer. Some but not all third party advertising companies provide a mechanism to opt-out of their technology. For more information and an identification of advertisers that provide an opt-out mechanism, please click here: [**http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp**](http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp). The information collected by third party cookies is subject to the privacy policy of the third party, not Demand Media's privacy policy.

3\. OUR USE AND RETENTION OF YOUR INFORMATION

3.1 _Use of PII_. We use your PII for such purposes as responding to your requests; operating the Site; providing you with advertising and non-advertising content that we believe would be of interest to you; enforcing our rights and the rights of third parties; and investigating and ensuring compliance with the [**Terms**](http://www.essortment.com/disclaimer.htm) and any other contract to which you and Demand Media are party.

3.2 _Use of Other Information_. We use non-PII for purposes such as measuring the number of visitors to our Site, making the Site more useful and delivering targeted advertising and non-advertising content. We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the Site, track a user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for non-personally identifiable use.

3.3 _Retention of Information_. We retain information for as long as required, allowed or we believe it useful, but do not undertake retention obligations. We may dispose of information in our discretion without notice, subject to applicable law that specifically requires the handling or retention of information. You must keep your own, separate back-up records.

4\. OUR SHARING OF INFORMATION

We share information with third parties, but only as described in this Section 4.

4.1 _Advertisers and Others_. We share non-personally identifiable information with advertisers, service providers, and other persons with whom we conduct business. 

4.2 _Service Third Parties_. We contract with affiliated and non-affiliated third parties to provide services to us or to you on our behalf. Examples include providing marketing assistance, sending email to you and analyzing data. These third parties may have access to personal information needed to perform their functions.

4.3 _Business Transfer_. As we develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses or their assets, or engage in acquisitions, mergers, restructurings, changes of control, or similar transactions. In such transactions, customer and user information generally is one of the transferred business assets, and your PII is subject to such a transfer. Also, in the unlikely event of a bankruptcy, customer and user information may be transferred to a bankruptcy trustee or debtor in possession and then to a subsequent purchaser.

4.4 _Promotions, Sweepstakes, and Contests_. From time to time, we may host a promotion, sweepstake or contest on the Site. You may be asked to provide personal information or permit the transfer to a third party of your personal information in connection with such promotion, sweepstake or contest. It will be disclosed at the point of collection or transfer who is collecting or transferring the information and whose privacy statement applies, and it will be your choice whether or not you wish to permit such transfer to or collection of personal information by a third party.

4.5 _Compliance and Safety_. We may release PII when we believe release is appropriate to:

  * comply with applicable law, and to respond to legal process, including subpoenas, search warrants and court orders, and to respond to or otherwise address written complaints of copyright infringement; 
  * make disclosures under programs intended to prevent potential crimes or investigate persons; 
  * enforce or apply agreements, including the Terms; or 
  * protect the rights, property, or safety of Demand Media or others, including exchanging information with other companies for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 

4.6 _Affiliates_. We may share PII, non-PII and other information with our corporate affiliates. Corporate affiliates are those entities that we control, are controlled by us, or are under common control with us and any joint venture in which any of the controlled entities may participate from time to time. Any use of your information by our corporate affiliates is subject to this Policy or another policy no less protective of your privacy. Likewise, we may obtain information about you from our corporate affiliates or from your visits to other websites that we or our corporate affiliates control. We may share information about you with our corporate affiliates and our corporate affiliates may share information with us using cookie or any other available technology. Some of our most significant affiliates are identified on the website of our parent company, Demand Media, Inc. (www.demandmedia.com).

5\. INFORMATION SECURITY

5.1 _Your Obligations_. You must protect against unauthorized access to your computer. Please sign off when finished using a shared computer. Your emails to us are not necessarily secure against interception so be careful about including sensitive information in them. YOU MUST DO WHAT YOU REASONABLY CAN TO ENSURE THE SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION.

5.2 _Our Security Measures_. We have physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to help safeguard, prevent unauthorized access, maintain data security, and correctly use your information. HOWEVER, WE DO NOT GUARANTEE SECURITY. Neither people nor security systems are foolproof, including encryption systems. In addition, people can commit intentional crimes, make mistakes or fail to follow policies. If applicable law imposes any non-disclaimable duty (if any), you agree that the standard used to measure our compliance with that duty will be one of intentional misconduct.

6\. LINKS

The Site contains links to unrelated third party sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Site and to read the privacy statements of every website that collects your personally identifiable information. This Policy applies only to information collected by the Site. 

7\. CHOICE

We reserve the right to send you customary business communications such as general system and administrative messages, address confirmations, and transactional information about the Site, and we may not offer you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving such communications. However, we provide you with the opportunity to elect not to receive other types of communications, such as newsletters. If you want to stop receiving these communications, we will provide you with an opt-out mechanism such as an "unsubscribe" tab on emails we send you.

8\. CONDITIONS OF USE, NOTICES, AND REVISIONS

8.1 _Privacy Concerns_. Your use of the Site and any dispute over privacy is subject to the [**Terms**](http://www.essortment.com/disclaimer.htm). If you have any concern about privacy at Demand Media, please send us a thorough description to [**legal@demandmedia.com**](mailto:legal@demandmedia.com) , and we will try to resolve it. If you think we are in default of the Terms, you may contact us at Our Legal Notices Address in Section 9 below.

8.2 _Notice Required by Law_. In those jurisdictions that permit email notice, if we are required to disclose or provide notice of invasion of certain security systems, we will do so by email to the most current email address provided by you to us. It is critical that you keep your email contact information correct and updated with us at all times.

8.3 _Identity Theft_. If you believe that you are a victim of identity theft entitled by law to request information from us, write us at our Legal Notices Address (see the next section of this Policy) and we will let you know what additional information you must provide to us. **After we have received that information, we will supply without charge the information legally required to be disclosed that we then have, subject to applicable law and reserving all of our rights and defenses.**

9\. CONTACT INFORMATION AND INFORMATION ABOUT ENFORCEMENT OF OUR POLICY

**Contacting Us & Our Address for Legal Notices; Notices to You.** To send us a legal notice, mail it by certified mail (return receipt requested) to: Demand Media, Inc., 1655 26th Street, Santa Monica, CA 90404, Attn: Legal Department. When we need to contact you, including when we give a legal notice, we may do so to an email address that we have on file for you, or we may post notice on the Site. You must keep your email address information accurate. If we make a material change to this Policy, we will notify you by posting notice to the Site for at least 30 days and, if we have an email address on record for you, sending you an email to that address.
